Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6140
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project
1937-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug amd Hospital Union
6140
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records.
5817054
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 21, 2001
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6085 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project "Frederick Douglass and His Time" Posters 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6089 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Posters 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6140 P: Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia
Health facilities -- Employees -- Labor unions; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions; Bread and Roses Cultural Project; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees.; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug & Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.)
5817054
- Moe Foner, 1978-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Moe Foner Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Moe Foner Correspondence, 1960-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Moe Foner Quotations (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Notes for Speeches (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Foner Brothers (Philip, Jack, Moe & Henry), 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Foner Brothers (Philip, Jack, Moe & Henry), 1960-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Art Exhibits, 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bread & Roses-1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bread & Roses-1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bread & Roses 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bread & Roses-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bread & Roses (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bread & Roses Publicity, 1984-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bread & Roses Photos (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Thursday's 'Til 9- Press Clippings (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Thursday's 'Til 9- Script (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Pins & Needles (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bread & Roses Gallery (Box 1, Folder 17)
- New York Council for the Humanities (Box 1, Folder 18)
- City of New York Mayor's Award of Honor for Arts & Culture Moe Foner, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ossie Davis & Ruby Dee, 1959-1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Paul Davis News Clippings & Publicity (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "Everything's Coming Up Bread & Roses" Progress Report, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ralph Fasanella, 1980-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Ralph Fasanella Exhibits & Calendar, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Gallery 1199-, 1972-1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Gallery 1199-Disarming Images, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Images of Labor, 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Lawrence MA Textile Strike (1912), 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Study Guides
- Lawrence MA Textile Strike (1912), 1979-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Articles & Clippings
- Postcard Series: Spanish Civil War, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Postcard Series: American Labor (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Postcard Series: International Women of Hope (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Postcard Series: Disarming Images (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Poster Series: "Women of Hope: African Americans who made a Difference", 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Poster Series: "Women of Hope: Latinas Abriendo Camino", 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Poster Series: "Women of Hope: Native American/Hawaiian", 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Poster Series: "Asian-American Women of Hope" (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Poster Series: "International Women of Hope", 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Poster Series: "Women of Hope" mixed series, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Women of Hope" Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Paul Robeson Centennial Celebration, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Paul Robeson Centennial Celebration (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Photographs
- Rochester & Binghamton Art & Theater Programs, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- "Take Care", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Publicity, reviews, correspondence, programs
- "Take Care, Take Care", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Articles, correspondence, publicity
- "Take Care III", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Programs, reviews, correspondence
- "Take Care", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Video production
- "Take Care IV", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Projected budget
- "Take Care" (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Publicity
- Maya Angelou, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 1199 Articles, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Contract Negotiations, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Contract Negotiations, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Contract Negotiations, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Leon Davis, 1960-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Leon Davis, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  An appreciation 1988, Memorial celebration 1992
- Leon Davis, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Interviews
- Leon Davis, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Correspondence
- Election Campaign Materials, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1199 History (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Labor History-The Great Depression (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1199-50s, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 1199-60s, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1199-70s, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1199-80s, 1989-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 1199-90s, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 1199-ND (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1199 Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1199 Publicity, 1963-1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 1199 Songs (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 1199 Photographs (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 1199 Housing Corporation: East River Urban Renewal Project (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1199 & Retail, wholesale, & department store union, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Unsung Heroes of 1199 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Elliot Godoff Tribute, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Hospital Strike-New York City, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Hospital Strike: Bronxville, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Hospital Strike: Charleston, SC [folder 1 of 2], 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Hospital Strike: Charleston, SC [folder 2 of 2], 1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Hospital Strike: 1976 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Hospital Strike: Columbia University (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Hospital Strikes (Box 3, Folder 28)
- King, Coretta Scott (Box 3, Folder 29)
- King, Dr. Martin Luther Jr. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Local 65 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Rivera, Dennis, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Seeger, Murray, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Article for Los Angeles Times
- Turner, Doris (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Unlawful Interference with Employees' Union Activity (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Jimmy Wechsler, 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Malcolm X (Box 3, Folder 38)